Aronson, Robert, Selected Files /4061
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Robert Aronson Selected Files
1968-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Aronson, Robert
/4061
15.5 cubic feet
15.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
3085137
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
AHolland, August 05, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, February 22, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers 4135 OHT: ILR School Founding Faculty Oral History Project /4191 AV: ILR School Audio-Visual Department Video Cassette Collection /4297: ILR School Biography Files 5267: Associated Actors and Artists Papers
Aronson, Robert Louis,1917-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3085137
- Accounts-Vouchers, etc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Proposal and Budget, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Case Study Plans and Notes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Project Staff, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Travel, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Binghamton (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cortland, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Elmira, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Progress Reports, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Paul M. Whalen - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- CETA - Rules and Regulations (Virgil H. Hodges) Jan 19, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Clippings, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Plant Shutdown Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Paul J. (Joe) Murphy, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Copies - Editing and Coding; Memos, Etc., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Joan Gibson, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Robert L. Chiaravalli, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Binghamton GAF, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Binghamton GAF, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Misc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Westinghouse - Elmira, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cortland Broadway, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Research Proposal, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Meeting with: Dean McKersie, Prof. Aronson, Jerry Moore, Tony Papalia, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bibliographies, Reference Inf., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Bibliographies, Lit. Survey, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Minutes from GAP Binghamton Interview w/, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Design (Frame work) for Data Collection (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence UAW: Papaua - Moore, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Robert L. Chiaravalli, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Fact Sheets, Minutes, "Study of Lab Dislocation" - GAP Report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Miscell.: Foltman Study (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Arbitration - Mack Trucks, Inc. EUAW, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Other Studies and Notes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Brockway Employees - Summary Statistics, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Brockway Shutdown in Cortland, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Project, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Continuity of Employment Study, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Tax Incentives and Financing Assistance for Industrial Location, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Coordinated Urban Economic Development (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound
- State Legislation, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- N.Y. State Dept. of Commerce Tax Incentives for Business Expansion, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- N.Y. State Dept. of Labor - Info on Unemployment Insurance Claimants, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence - other, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Manpower Admin., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Community Manpower Study Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Interviews, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Misc. Documents County Data, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Syracuse Manpower Plan, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Community Manpower Study Notes, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Com. Manpower Study Report, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Employment Service Binghamton, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Tables Ears Output MA Series, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Esars Handbook Employment Service Bureau, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Esars Output Report New York State, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Esars Handbook Chapter 7, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Manpower at the Grass Roots, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Huron Copysette Manifold Carbon Paper Sets (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Huron Copysette Manifold Carbon Paper Sets (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Misc. Documents NYC Dept. of Labor, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Questionnaire, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Universe of Need Worksheets, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Expected Turnover Old Age Social Workers, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Kay Moore, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- T.C. Youth Employment Project, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Gold, Charlotte, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Manpower Grant, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- USDOL - Res. Proposal (Extra Copies, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Manpower Grant Administrative, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Barocci, Thomas, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Kaufman, Debra, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Raudabaugh, John, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Henry Wan Jr., 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- David Whetten, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Dead File, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Howard Aldrich, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Elizabeth Durbin, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- George Farkas, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Francis, Barbara, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Harrison, Bennett, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Howard Garland, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Lichtenstein, Jules, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Linda Leathers, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Burton Leathers, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Lewis Perl, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Werner Sengenberger, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Galenson, Marjorie (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Vladimir Stoikov, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Outside Review, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- ILR Faculty Research Manuel, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Faculty Legislation, 1979-1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Directory of ILR Faculty Members, 1975-1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- ILR Faculty Policy&; Procedures, 1981-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- University Grievance Committee, 1973-1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- ILR Faculty, 1965-1988 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Annual Reports, 1982-1990 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Health Careers Program, 1989-1994 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Health Careers Program, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Faculty Tennis Club, 1976-1991 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Goldfield File, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- AAUP, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- By- Laws of Cornell University, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- CISER: Cornell Institute for Social and Economic Research, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Association of Cornell University Emeritus Professors: Emeritus Professors- 10/10/89, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Association of Cornell University Emeritus Professors Surveys, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Association of Cornell University Emeritus Professors, 1982-1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Standing Committees, 1978-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Graduate Students- Standards and Practices, 1968-1988 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- ILR Departments, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Promotion Committee- Hutchens, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Labor Economics, 1973-1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- ILR 540, 1964-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- ILR 9740 (Baruch)- Administrative, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Labor Economics Department- 1978 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Letters of Recommended Students, 1969-1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Graduate Students, 1964-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1980-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- ILR Correspondence, 1977-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Personal, 1977-1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- External Examiner- UWI, 1985-1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Agreement- Workers and Industrial Change, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Cornell Arbitration, 1978-1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- ILR Review Board, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- ILR Review Board, 1970-1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Aronson- Book Reviews, 1947-1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- ILR Review- 1969-70 Manuscript Comments, 1969-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- ILR Graduate Reunion- Atlantic Georgia- 1986: Letters and Addresses (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Personal Matters, 1959-1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Retirement, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- RLA- Vita, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- "Unionism Among Professional Employees in the Private Sector"- Robert Aronson and Sharon Stout, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Manuscript Scientist & Engineer Employment, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Ohio State- Economists, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- "Unionism Among Professional Employees in the Private Sector"- Aronson, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Newark Valley Enrollment, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- "Manpower at the Grass-Roots: Prospectus on the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act of 1973"- Aronson, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- MS Original- "Components of Occupational Change in the United States 1950-1960"- Aronson, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Aronson Publications, 1949-1965 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Aronson Publications and Committees, 1959-1973 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Aronson Publications and Misc. Journals/Articles, 1950-1975 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  Contains German Language
- "Skilled Manpower Development: Review of Literature with Implications for Research"- Aronson, Cullen, and Foltman (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Gradebooks '60- '79, 1960-1979 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Gradebooks '79- '84, 1979-1984 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Professional Unionism Notes- Codes and Votes (Box 11, Folder 1)
- ILR 646 Course Outline, 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- ILR 446- "Labor Problems of the College Educated- Term Report Instructions", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- ILR 646 Bibliography, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Labor Problems of the College Educated Paper Assignments and Seminar, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Growth of the Professions and the College- Trained Workforce, 1976-1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Sources and Nature of Demand, 1976-1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Social Origins of the College- Trained and Professional Labor Force, 1957-1987 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Occupational Choices of the College- Trained, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Job Outlook for College Graduates, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Employment of High-Skill College Graduates and Notes, 1976-1983 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Unemployment and Underemployment, 1975-1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Shortages in High- Talent Labor Markets, 1978-1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- The Adjustment Process, 1976-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Productivity and Substitution in the Demand for Professional Occupations, 1970-1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Employment and Science Funding by the Reagan Administration, 1970-1985 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Nature of Professions and Professional Work, 1955-1982 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Professional Associations, 1975-1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Occupational Licensing and Other Controls, 1976-1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Determinants of Professional Income, 1976-1981 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Employment Discrimination, 1974-1979 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- The Process of Professionalization, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Self Employment and Misc. Articles, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Unionism Among Professional Employees, 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Unions and Professions, 1985-1988 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Unions and Professions, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Unions and Professions, 1976-1988 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- The Role of Colleges and Universities, 1978-1982 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Supply and Demand of Colleges, 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Employment Attributes of Recent Science and Engineering Graduates, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Aronson Bibliography and Sources, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Aronson: "Community Costs of Plant Closings: Bibliography and Survey of the Literature" Prepared for the Federal Trade Commission, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Need for an Industrial Policy, 1980-1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Role of Technology, 1974-1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Measurement of Plant Closing, 1978-1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Case Studies: Washington Electric Corporation, Closing of Ford Motor Company Plant in Mahwah, New Jersey, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Case Studies, 1960-1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Foreign Trade Aspects, 1983-1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Welfare Impacts, 1976-1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Employment and Earnings Impacts, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Employment and Earnings Impacts, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Public Programs- U.S., 1979-1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Public Programs- U.S., 1974-1983 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Public Programs- Foreign, 1979-1982 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Employee Ownership, 1979-1983 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Collective Bargaining and Union Responses, 1978-1983 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Other Private Approaches, 1979-1988 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- "Graduate Business Education and the M.B.A."- Edward Vaimberg, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Manpower Policy and CETA (Box 12, Folder 22)
- ILR 640 Notes, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- West Genesee School District Settlement, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Elmira- CSEA, 1988 M87-469 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Watkins Glen Central School District 1988, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Watkins Glen M89-108, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Watkins Glen Municipal Employment, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Elmira Central School District- CMCW, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Endicott- PBA, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Newark Velley School District, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Romulus Central School District, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Elmira Central School District- ISEA, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Corning Police M92-203, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Fayetteville- Manlius '93, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Seneca Falls Police, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- American Arbitration Association, 1954-1985 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- CSEA v. Newark Valley Central School District, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- FMCS, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- St. Lawrence Co.- Lab. (AAA), 1978 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Owasco Highway Department, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- IAMAW v. Morse Chain AAA 15 30 0484 79, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Misc. Robert Aronson Folder, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Prisoners Grievances, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 21)
- CU Employee Grievance Procedure, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Promotion of Robert S. Smith (U. of Rochester) (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Tenured School Employees, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Town of Geddes, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Town of Geddes Highway vs. United Steelworkers, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Town of Geddes Rebuttals and Responses to the Union, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- PERB Administrative, 1971-1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- PERB- Bulletin, 1988-1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- PERB- Law and Procedures, 1974-1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- PERB Miscellaneous, 1971-1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- PERB Mandatory Subjects (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Cases, 1970-71, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Cases, 1971-72, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Cases, 1973-73 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Cases, 1975-76, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- PERB Cases- 1976-77, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- PERB 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- City of Elmira vs. The Elmira Police Benevolent Association, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Elmira Heights Central School District vs. Elmira Heights Staff Association, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Trumansburg M85-162: Trumansburg Central School District vs. Trumansburg Teachers Association, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Dundee School District vs Dundee Non instructional Staff, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Binghamton School District, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Windsor Central School District vs. Windsor Employees Custodial & Transportation Staff, 1968-1981 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Newark Valley Highway Department, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 21)
- Union- Endicott School District, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Seneca Falls School District vs. Seneca Falls Teacher's Association, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Articles on Leisure and Work Schedules, 1956-1983 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Automation, 1960-1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Collective Bargaining, 1980-1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Collectively Bargaining- Public Sector, 1969-1989 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Consumer Prices, 1961-1978 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Discrimination, 1972-1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Education, 1967-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Employment, 1967-1985 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Foreign Trade, 1963-1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Income Distribution, 1973-1985 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Labor and Economic Development, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Labor Force, 1984-1991 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Labor Mobility, 1960-1980 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Labor Supply, 1958-1989 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Labor Supply: "The Demographic Structure of Unemployment Rates and Labor Market Transition Probabilities"- Ronald Ehrenberg, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Manpower and Economic Development, 1962-1981 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Manpower, 1961-1975 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Manpower Forecasting, 1964-1966 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Manpower Projections, 1967-1974 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Migration, 1965-1980 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  French and German Language
- Minimum Wage, 1961-1990 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Professional Unions, 1972-1991 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous Reprints, 1947-1979 (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Negro Employment, 1963-1981 (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Occupations, 1966-1980 (Box 15, Folder 25)
- Old-Age Benefits, 1952-1982 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Poverty, 1966-1982 (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Productivity, 1967-1977 (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Professional Manpower, 1967-1992 (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Manpower- Military, 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- New York Times- "Downsizing of America" Series, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Technological Change, 1948-1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Scientists and Engineers, 1966-1972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Trade Unions, 1956-1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Unemployment, 1959-1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Unemployment Insurance, 1960-1977 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Unionism, 1947-1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Wages, 1962-1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Wage Structure, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Wage Policy, 1962-1980 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- CETA: "Manpower at the Grass-Roots: Prospectus on the Comprehensive Employment and Training Act of 1973" and Memorandum to Dean McKersie, 1974- 1975 (Box 16, Folder 11)